[bright music]
[vegetable rustling]
- [Hiraku] In between
winter and summer,
the number of residents
increased again.
After discussing,
we decided to call this place
the Great Tree Village.
And I ended up
becoming the mayor.
But even though
I'm the mayor now,
my day-to-day routine
hasn't really changed at all.
[hammer tapping]
[bright music]
Huh?
- Mayor.
There's a messenger from
the Demonic Kingdom.
- From the Demonic Kingdom?
["Flower Ring" by Shino Shimoji
and Aya Suzaki plays]
[dramatic musical sting]
- Greetings, I am Beezel.
I'd like to meet with
the person in charge here.
- It's my first job
as the mayor.
That's me.
[Beezel scoffs]
- [Beezel] You?
- That's right.
I'm the mayor, Hiraku.
- Very well, in honor
of our acquaintance,
please accept this gift.
[Lu gasps]
- Thank you for your generosity.
- I have a message to deliver
from the Demon Lord.
He would like to discuss
the status of this settlement.
[Hiraku gasps]
- I don't think anyone owns
this plot of land or anything,
but I guess it's under the
control of the Demon Lord.
- Does he want me to pay taxes
for all the time I've spent
living on his land?
No.
Maybe he's gonna tell me
to get off his property.
Maybe it would be wise for me
to ask Lu and Tia
for their advice
before I do anything.
Enough.
It's time for me to step up
and handle my duties as mayor.
All right.
If the Demon Lord accepts us
living here on this land,
then I will offer part of
our harvest for taxes.
First, I need to show that I
have no intention of rebelling.
As for the percentage we pay,
I need to be strong
for this part,
how does 10% sound?
[dramatic music]
Crap, was that too low?
[Beezel grunts]
- Well, then.
[Hiraku grunts]
Are you satisfied with this?
- Wait, what?
I am.
I'd like you to come pick it up
every year before winter.
- Very well, I understand.
That's how we will
proceed from now on.
- [Hiraku] Huh?
Is it settled already?
The tax will be 10%
of our total harvest.
However, this is limited to
what we grow in our fields.
We won't give them any
milk, eggs, honey,
or alcohol that we produce.
If the Demon Lord is
interested in anything else
then we'll enter
trade negotiations.
[Beezel and Hiraku sigh]
I did feel like I was too
aggressive with my negotiations.
- I bid you all farewell.
- So I sent him home
with a present.
I hope I handled that
the right way.
- I think you did
a pretty good job.
Since we're paying them taxes,
we're technically under
the Demon Lords protection
from now on.
- Yes, indeed.
But even still,
[giggles] only 10%?
Usually the going rate is
supposed to be 50 or 60%.
- What?
- Having them come to
collect the payment
was a good decision.
It forces them to
officially recognize
our residents
in the forest.
- And if they're only coming
to collect once a year,
they won't be able to measure
everything we produce.
In other words, we just bought
the protection of the Demon Lord
for a real tax rate
of under 10%.
- Well done, Mayor Hiraku.
- Really?
- And to top it off,
they brought this present,
medicine that works if you drink
it or apply it to an injury.
- Wow.
- [Grattz] What?
They're submitting to
our military force?
- [Beezel] Yes.
- [Grattz] Even though they have
the strength to defeat wyvern?
- Surely they're
up to something.
- I had the same suspicion.
I had no choice but to
accept their offer.
- [Randan] But why?
- The Vampire Princess
and Angel of Annihilation.
- [Grattz] What?
The great sage, Lulucy, and
the strongest of all the angels?
- No way! [shivers]
- [Beezel] And that's not all.
There was an army of high elves
and a pack of inferno wolves.
- [Grattz] You're joking.
- And the group that
guided me to their leader
was the trio of Killer Angels.
I thought my life was over.
- [Grattz] [groans]
If that's it,
then I see how they were
able to take down wyvern.
- Then he suggested that
they be under the protection
of the Demon Lord's army.
I could not refuse.
If I had, they would've
immediately gathered
to become an enemy force.
- No way.
- [Beezel] Silver lining
in all of this
is that we were able to
negotiate amicably.
They even gave me a gift.
- Oh?
What do you think it is?
- I haven't looked yet.
- Open it.
- [Beezel] We need to
consult the Demon Lord.
- [Randan] It's over,
we're finished.
- [Grattz] And what if
it's something dangerous?
[wrapping paper tearing]
- Hey, wait!
- Hmm, fruit?
They look like appos,
but the shape and color
are much nicer.
Better check if they're
poisoned. [munches]
- Hey!
- Whoa, this is really good.
It's great.
- You can't just go
and eat those.
[bright music]
Oh.
This cloth.
It can't.
Is this from a demon spider?
No, a great demon spider.
- You're joking.
Didn't one of those fight one
of the previous Demon Lords
to a standstill?
They have one of those too?
- I'm resigning.
- Randan!
Randan!
[leaves rustling]
- Uh.
[dramatic music]
- My name is Dryme.
I am the one true
ruler of the Dragons.
[light upbeat music]
- This is a present
from Lord Dryme.
We hope you will accept it.
- Sure.
Wow, it looks really expensive,
but it seems like kind of
a violent gift.
Thank you for
the wonderful gift.
It's lovely.
- [Gucci] It's our pleasure.
- So what's the purpose of your
visit
to the Great Tree Village today?
- Right.
My good master, Lord Dryme,
has his lair located
just to the south of here.
There's quite a bit of
distance between us,
however we consider
you our neighbors.
We've come here to offer
a formal greeting.
- That's very polite
of you, sir.
By the way, is there any
particular reason
that your master is
bowing his head?
- My deepest apologies
for that, good sir.
Master, would you kindly
please raise your head?
- What? Sure.
- Since you came
all the way here
I'd like to invite you inside,
but that seems hard
given your size.
- You're absolutely right.
Master, please change
into your smaller form.
[Dryme grunts]
[smoke whooshes]
[light cheery music]
Now, introduce yourself again.
- My name is Dryme.
I am the one true
ruler of the Dragons.
- [Hiraku] Okay, I wonder
if he memorized that line
so he wouldn't mess up
his introduction.
- Man, this place is great.
This booze is great.
I'm never going home.
I'm gonna live right here.
- You can't do that.
There will be a lot of people
who will get very upset
if you don't protect your home.
- I'll be fine here.
I can intercept any attackers.
- I know that, master.
However, it would be a
nuisance for everyone here
if you were to stay too long.
[Dryme groans]
Now let's be on our way
while they're still happy
to call us their guests.
They were even kind enough
to gift to us.
- [Dryme] Oh yeah.
They give us those
appo-looking things.
- They're called apples
and don't worry they
gave us plenty of them.
- [Dryme] Yeah, yeah, whatever.
I'm heading home.
- Don't transform yet
until you're outside, okay?
- [Dryme] Wee, I'm flying!
[wings whooshing]
- I know I should have
thought of this sooner
but I should really decide
how the Great Tree Village
is going to handle visitors,
welcome guests or otherwise,
diplomatic relations.
Ugh, this is all getting
complicated really fast.
I've been thinking about
a lot of things since then,
and I believe it's not good
for us to keep visitors outside
when greeting them.
With that said, I'm not
comfortable inviting them in.
So I've decided that
we should build
a guest house for visitors.
I was thinking a house
able to fit four people
would be enough.
- [Lea] No, I think that
would be far too small.
- Right, anyone coming
to this village
needs to climb mountains
and make it safely
through the forest.
Our visitors up until now
have been servants
of the Demon Lord or dragons.
However, normally when
people come here
they'll be doing it
in large groups.
- If that's the case, then I
think we should play it safe
and build a house that can
fit 30 people comfortably.
- 30?
- [Lea] We'll make the
first floor an open space
designed to hold feasts.
- And we can make the
second floor into bedrooms
for our guests if they
wanna stay a bit longer.
- Hmm, that works.
[bright cheery music]
And that's how we got started
building a guest house
for any potential visitors.
Next, I wanted to work on
how we greet new guests.
Granmaria and the angels
are in charge of
defending the perimeter.
[swords flicking]
And rather than finding visitors
and guiding them here,
they would capture visitors
and bring them to
the village entrance.
On top of that, when Zabuton
sounded the warning alarm,
everyone would
grab their weapons
and get ready for battle.
It's a long way off
from a proper welcome.
So we came up with a
new signal for visitors.
[bell ringing]
Lea and the elves made a bell.
Next, we discussed how
we treated our guests.
I suggested that Lu, Tia,
and I would be the ones
to greet the guests.
- I cannot agree with using
such a small welcoming party.
- She's right on that.
Enemies might take advantage
and sneak in
disguised as visitors.
- [sighs] My idea was rejected,
so we added a few high elves,
a scattering of ogre maids,
and lizardmen to
our welcoming party.
Flora wanted to be part of
our welcoming party as well,
but I asked her to keep
an eye on any visitors
that stay here until night fall.
- Understood.
Please leave it to me.
If you'd like,
I can keep watch the
entire time they're here.
- That's when I learned
that Flora and Lu
could go several days
without sleeping and be fine,
but I still told them
not to overdo it.
[bell ringing]
All the preparation
we did got put to use,
much sooner than I expected.
- My name is Garf.
We have traveled from
a place in the mountains
east of here called
Howling Village.
We want to establish
relations with your village.
- Let me handle this.
That must have been
a tough journey.
The Great Tree Village
welcomes you.
- We thank you.
- I would like to take you
to our guest house
so that you can rest.
Are these all of the
travelers in your group?
- Yes, they are.
- [Lu] I see.
Then we'll treat
the others as enemies.
- [Hiraku] What's she
talking about?
[canines growling]
- [Garf] Hmm, sorry about that.
It looks like we had
a few stragglers.
- Well, that was dangerous.
You should really make sure
everyone is together
before you enter the village.
And it would be wise of you
to behave yourselves
while you're here.
There are people that even I
need to watch myself around.
- I understand.
You have my word.
- Then follow me
to our guest house.
- Welcome to our village.
- [All] Welcome to our village.
[beastmen gasping]
- [[Hiraku] Great, we've
taken our first step
towards real hospitality.
- Stay here and enjoy
yourselves please.
[beastmen chattering]
[lock thuds]
- What are you doing?
It seems more like you're
trapping enemies
than welcoming guests.
- [Tia] Mayor,
haven't you noticed.
- [Hiraku] Huh?
- When visitors come to
establish relations,
they always bring some
sort of offering with them.
Even that dragon
brought something.
- You think they
aren't friendly?
- I can't say for sure exactly.
If they don't follow
the normal rules,
then they don't get the
normal visitor treatment.
- I see.
- I'm concerned about
them leaving
two troops hiding
in the woods.
That's why we knocked
our hospitality level
down a notch or two for them.
- Didn't Kudel or the other
girls spot those troops
while making their way
through the forest?
- They noticed them
but decided those troops weren't
a threat and ignored them.
I planned to
punish them all later.
- Go easy on them.
- I'll let them off
with a warning.
[food sizzling]
[Hiraku groans]
- [Anne] Is something
the matter?
- Oh, it's nothing.
It's just that the food
you made for Dryme-
- Do you think this
isn't up to par?
- Well, something like that.
- I'm sure that you've
realized by now,
but this is the treatment
for guests who bring nothing.
- I see.
Oh, so does that mean
you don't plan on
offering them any wine?
[Anne groans]
I see.
[beastmen chattering]
I feel terrible offering
them such a meager meal.
- Please erase yourself
of such emotions.
- She's right.
They're here for
important negotiations.
Our goal is to find out
exactly what they're after.
- Everyone besides you
was completely against
offering them any wine.
You forced us to
give it to them.
- [Beastmen] Cheers.
- And I'm glad that
you all let me do it.
That said, it's just
two cups per person.
[beastman retches]
Those were the restrictions
put in place.
The fact remains,
they came all the way here.
Until we determined
they're enemies,
I wanna show them kindness.
First, I wanna find out
why they're here.
Uh, I'm sure I'm revealing my
own ignorance in asking this,
but just what kind of place
is Howling Village?
- Well, some say
it's been around
for over a thousand years,
but in reality,
I think it's really only been
about 500 years or so.
Man, those older guys sure take
pride in the weirdest stuff.
- You got that right.
[beastmen laugh]
- What we call Howling Village
is a place
of five small settlements of
about a hundred people or so
and most of the population
are beastmen.
- You got that right. [laughs]
- Howling Village is
made up of people
who make their living
hunting or mining.
Up until now, they've managed
to survive by trading
with a human village
across the mountains.
But lately there's been
some trouble there
and the trade between them
has become unstable.
That's why they're looking for
someone new to trade with
and they settled on
our Great Tree Village.
So where did you learn
about our village?
- We got word from one of
the Demon Lord's people.
- Huh?
- Man, if we stayed outside
hiding the whole time
we would've missed
this great meal.
I'm so glad we didn't.
- Why were you hiding
in the first place?
- You need to be on guard
for the first visit.
Plus, if something were
to happen there
someone needs to go back and
tell the rest of the village.
- [Tia] Oh?
- [Hiraku] She's doing a good
job of gathering information.
I can count on her.
[bright cheery music]
[beastmen chattering]
It turned out that the beast men
from Howling Village
weren't trying to trick us.
They really did want
trade relations.
- Now then let's talk about
our trade agreement.
- Yes.
- Our trade's different.
We trade physical goods
in an open market.
After all, we don't use any
currency in our village.
- That's the same as here.
Currency, huh?
I'm sure we'll need to
create it someday.
- Normally I'd want to open up
a market in both villages
but, if you can, we'd like you
to come to ours to trade.
The truth is it was very
difficult for us
to even get here
with our goods.
- Oh?
- Carrying them here and
back would be too much.
- It would be pretty much the
same for us to travel as well.
- But you live here.
Aren't you able to navigate
the forest easily?
- [Hiraku] Now that
he mentions it,
maybe I can have Kuro and the
dogs carry the goods for us.
I understand.
- Huh?
- What would you like
for our first trade?
- Well, we have
lots of goods
made from the ore
that we mine.
We have things like paints,
silverware, glassworks,
and also metal works.
- I want them, I wanna
have all of that stuff!
- In exchange we'd like to get
some of the food you grow.
- Then we'll bring
our food crops to trade
at the open market.
- Ah.
- [Hiraku] And so began
our trade relationship
with Howling Village.
[leaves rustling]
- About the present thing.
- Hmm?
- The truth is,
until now I didn't know
people brought gifts
when visiting.
Our village doesn't have
a custom like that.
- Oh, that's okay,
don't worry about it.
- I'll bring
something next time.
With that being said,
our village is poor,
so we won't be able to
bring anything fancy.
- Right, that's fine.
What's important isn't
the value of the gift
but the thought behind it.
- Ah, hearing that from you
makes me feel better.
[bright music]
- I was planning on going
to the market as well.
- You can't,
it looks bad if we send
our top man there right away.
- Is that how it works?
- That's how it works.
We drew lots and based on that,
I'll be acting on your behalf
for the duration while there.
- [Hiraku] Originally it was
going to take 10 days
for them to travel,
but Dryme agreed
to take everyone there
in exchange for
a barrel of wine.
After his first visit,
Dryme started to come here
to hang out regularly.
[Dryme groans]
He always brings us gifts of
treasures or weapons with him
so no one complains.
Transporting everyone in
exchange for a barrel of wine
was actually Dryme's idea.
So I took him up on the offer.
- Okay then, we'll off now.
- Thanks for the wine, mayor.
- Sure.
[wings crashing]
[birds chirping]
- Are they really
going to show up?
Well, Garf worked out the
trade agreement with them.
They'll be here.
- We haven't even received word
that they've reached
the mountain range yet.
[wings flapping]
- Huh?
Is that?
- [Beastman] A dragon!
- Yeah, and it's coming
straight this way.
Look at that.
[upbeat music]
Good work, everyone.
How was it?
- We were able to exchange
everything we took
and they loved it all.
They seemed to be
hesitant at first
because they wouldn't go
near anything we brought,
but then I tried the free sample
stuff you told me about
and before I knew it, a crowd
of beast people had gathered.
- They sold the wine that was
supposed to be for me.
- Did they?
I guess you'll
just have to drink
even more at dinner tonight.
- You're the best.
You really know
how to cheer me up.
- In addition to that,
the mayor of Howling Village
wanted to know
if some of their people
could come and live here.
- [grunts] We need
more people to work,
so I'd be glad to have them.
- There are 20 people that
want to come live here
and they're all young women.
- The fact of the matter is
that right now
this village is in desperate
need of more men.
If this keeps up, I'm afraid
the village won't have a future.
Fine, but I have one condition.
If they can send
at least two young men,
then I'll happily
accept everyone.
- Understood, mayor.
[upbeat music]
- [Hiraku] Now the future of
the village is secure.
[Sena whimpering]
- Hello, my name is Sena.
We are all very grateful
that you have accepted us
into your village.
We're mentally prepared for you
to use us however you see fit,
just please don't
abandon us later on.
- Uh, I see you've gone
through a lot to prepare
for your move here.
Anyways, we've got
your beds ready.
Take your time and
get acclimated.
- You want us to take our time?
- Yes, please.
Once you're used to
daily life here,
you can make requests for
what kind of house you want.
You don't need to
worry about us
kicking you out
or anything.
- Thank you so much, mayor.
- Of course.
By the way, are
the men here with you?
- They are.
We have brought three
of them along with us.
[bright music]
[children gasping]
We brought you some young men
like you asked of us.
- [Hiraku] Okay.
No, wait, maybe five years,
or maybe 10 years from now.
I'm counting on you for
the future of this village!
["Feel the winds"
by Yui Hizuki plays]
[rustic music playing]